Register of the M. P. (Mariia Petrovna) Bok Papers, 1896-1970
Hoover Institution Archives
M. P. (Mariia Petrovna) Bok Papers,
1896-1970
2000C16
Bok, M. P. (Mariia Petrovna), b. 1885
2 microfilm reels. (0.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, correspondence, clippings, and photographs, relating to Petr Stolypin.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Access Points
Stolypin, Petr Arkad'evich, 1862-1911.; Russia--Politics and government--1894-1917.; Russia.
Biography
Daughter of the Russian statesman Petr Stolypin.
Scope and Content
This collection consists mainly of newspaper clippings relating to and photographs of M. P. Bok's father, Petr Arkad'evich Stolypin. There is a small amount of correspondence, as well as biographical material relating to Bok's husband, naval officer Boris Ivanovich Bok.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials and copyright to them (with some exceptions) are the property of the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1953-1966, Box 1
  Letters to M. P. Bok and B. I. Bok arranged alphabetically by correspondent
  - General, 1958-1965 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - Bilimovich, Aleksandr D., 1956 (Folder 2)
  - Magerovskii, Lev Florianovich, 1953 (Folder 3)
  - Meyendorff, Alexander F., Baron, 1955-1957 (Folder 4)
  - Penionzhkevich, Iu., 1965-1966. Includes brochure by Penionzhkevich entitled Zabytyi dolg russkoi emigratsii (São Paolo, 1965) (Folder 5)
  - Polushkin, Nikolai Sergeevich, 1956 (Folder 6)
  - Zen'kovskii, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, 1953-1956 (Folder 7)
- Writings, 1935-1948. Serialized excerpts from memoirs, Box 1
  Two versions of M. P. Bok's memoirs, serialized in the Russian émigré press, arranged chronologically
  - "Zhizn' P. A. Stolypina: Vospominaniia ob otsie," Vozrozhdenie, 1935-1936. Printed copy (Box 1., Folder 8)
  - "Iz vospominanii ob otsie," Russkaia zhizn', 1948. Printed copy (Folder 9)
- Stolypin File, 1896-1970, Boxes 1-2
  Materials relating to P. A. Stolypin, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Articles and brochures (Box 1., Folder 10)
  - Clippings (Folder 11)
  - Scrapbooks. Consist mainly of photographs, but include a brief family history and copies of documents, as well as a handwritten note by Stolypin (Box 2., Folder 1-2)
  - Speech on Stolypin by Baron Vladimir Aleksandrovich Barkov, 1930 (Folder 3)
  - Miscellany. Includes correspondence of Baron A. F. Meyendorff with Stephen Graham, George Gooch and Richard Enfield, 1949-1950, regarding publication of a biography of Stolypin, as well as fragments of drafts and background materials apparently intended for such a work, reviews of Zen'kovskii's biography, and the program of the 1896 Imperial coronation ceremonies in Moscow (Folder 4)
- Oversize File, 1950-1951., Box 2
  Addresses, clippings, and correspondence congratulating B. I. Bok on his 50 years of military service
  - Addresses, clippings, and correspondence congratulating B. I. Bok on the 50th anniversary of his commission as a naval officer (Box 2., Oversize 5)